Guide to the Birge M. Clark Architectural Drawings SC0838
Department of Special Collections and University Archives
Birge M. Clark architectural drawings
1909-1954
Department of Special Collections and University Archives
Clark, Birge M. (Birge Malcolm)
SC0838
2000 item(s)
Collection contains architectural drawings by Birge M. Clark, his brother David B. Clark, and other partners Walter Stromquist, David F. Potter and Joseph Ehrlich, with a few drawings by his father A. B. Clark. Projects were mostly located in Palo Alto, Stanford, and other communities on the Peninsula and included residences, schools, businesses, and city offices. Most of the drawings are pencil on tissue but other formats are also represented.
Other Finding Aids
Index to Stanford homes: http://purl.stanford.edu/tp324pd7026
Biographical/Historical Sketch
Birge M. Clark began his architectural practice in Palo Alto after World War I, when he helped his father A. B. Clark with the design of Herbert and Lou Henry Hoover's home on the Stanford campus. He went on to design many homes and businesses in Palo Alto, including the Post Office, the Lucie Stern Community Center, and the Hewlett-Packard plant. His contributions to Stanford's architecture include the Seeley G. Mudd Chemistry Building and the John Stauffer Chemical Laboratories.
Description of the Collection
Collection contains architectural drawings by Birge M. Clark, his brother David B. Clark, and other partners Walter Stromquist, David F. Potter and Joseph Ehrlich, with a few drawings by his father A. B. Clark. Projects were mostly located in Palo Alto, Stanford, and other communities on the Peninsula and included residences, schools, businesses, and city offices. Most of the drawings are pencil on tissue but other formats are also represented.
Architects.; School buildings -- California -- Design and construction.; Architecture, Domestic -- California; Clark, Arthur Bridgman; Potter, David F.; Stromquist, Walter.; Clark, Birge M. (Birge Malcolm); Ehrlich, Joseph.; Clark, Birge M. (Birge Malcolm); Clark, David B.
- Architectural Drawings
  - Parks, Professor George S., 1927-07-02; 286 (Box Sc7)
    Scope and Contents note
    6 sheets - Site plan, garage, plans, section, elevation, details
    Address: 162 Alvarado
    City: Stanford
    Category: residence
    Architect: Clark, Birge M.
  - Osborne, George E., 1929-12; 342 (Box Sc9)
    1 drawing
    Address: 669 Cabrillo
  - Duncan, W. B., 1930-02-26; 343
    Address: 275 Fernando
  - Miles, Walter, 1925; 247 (Box Sd9)
    5 drawings
    Address: 607 Gerona
  - Alpha Delta Phi, 1937; 451 (Box Sc5)
    9 plans
    Address: 579 Lasuen
    Architect: Clark, Birge M. and David B. Clark
  - Phi Gamma Delta, 1935, 1937; 397 (Box Sc4)
    4 plans
    Address: 630 Lasuen
  - Fairman, Charles, 1939; 496 (Box Sb9)
    Address: Los Arboles Ave
  - Shaw, Edward S., 1940; 518 (Box Sb9)
    Address: Los Arboles
    City: Stanford, CA
  - Moser, Charles, 1927-08-26; 287 (Box Sc7)
    7 drawings, 1927
    Address: Lot #6 Foothill [Lot #6, Foothill subdivision]
  - Lee, V. A., 1935, 1938; 408 (Box Sc4)
    3 plans
    Address: 440 Foothill Rd.
  - Culver, George B., 1931-06-26; 354 (Box Sc9)
    Address: 684 Foothill Rd.
  - Hansen, W. W., 1940-08-10; 524 (Box Sb9)
    4 plans, 1940
    Address: Gerona & Foothill
  - Davis, W. H., 1925-06-09; 237
    Address: Mayfield & Coronado
  - McDaniel, H. B., 1948-11-03; 681 (Box Sc3)
    6 sheets
    Address: 514 Mayfield Avenue
    Architect: Clark, Birge M. and Walter Stromquist
  - Jungeblut, Dr. C. W., 1928; 313 (Box Sc7)
    10 drawings
    Address: 574 Foothill Rd.
  - Theta Delta Chi, 1937; 449 (Box Sc5)
    2 plans
    Address: 584 Mayfield
  - Hoover, Lou Henry, 1924-10-24; 215 (Box Sc11)
    Group of 5 houses, approx. 30 items, pencil on tissue except for 1 blueprint plot map
    Address: 615 Mayfield
  - Hoover, Lou Henry, 1926-1928; 248 (Box Sd9)
    7 drawings, 1925 (sheets 1, 2, 3, 5, 6, 7 and one unnumbered sheet)
    Address: 622 Salvatierra
  - Stoltenberg, Dr. Clara, 1931-10-14; 358 (Box Sc4)
    Plans, 1931 and 1938
    Address: 525 Salvatierra
  - Stoltenberg, Dr. Clara, 1939-10-05; 503
    Address: 525 Salvatierra - additions
  - Townley, S. D., 1921-08-18; 40 (Box Sc1)
    5 sheets: details, floor plans, elevations, kitchen & dining room; A. B. Clark, 1921, pencil tracings
    Address: 613 Salvatierra
    Architect: Clark, A. B.
  - Green, Boynton M., 1927-09-14; 289 (Box Sc7)
    6 drawings
    Address: 691 Salvatierra [Lot #190]
  - Barnett, G. D., 1920-07; 31 (Box Sc1)
    2 Sheets + 2 sheets: Plan & Elevations; Details; A. B. Clark, pencil tracings
    Address: San Juan Hill
  - Crook, W. J., 1921-09-14; 41 (Box Sc1)
    5 sheets: elevations, plans, kitchen details, other details; A. B. Clark, pencil tracings
    Address: 675 San Juan
  - Culver, George B., 1936-02-27; 413 (Box Sc5)
    3 drawings (plans, elev, details)
    Address: Santa Teresa past Gov. Lane
  - Pi Beta Phi, 1940; 521 (Box Sb9)
    Alterations to, 2 plans
    Address: Santa Ynez & Mayfield
  - Storey, Dean, 1941-10-22; 556 (Box Sc2)
    Address: 746 Santa Ynez Avenue
  - Stone, Mrs. Evelyn, 1940-06-19; 519 (Box Sb9)
    3 plans, 1940
    Address: 262 Searsville Rd.
  - Lapiere, Richard T., 1940-07-26; 523 (Box Sb9)
    Address: 268 Searsville Rd.
  - Jordan, D. S., 1923-08-06; 186
    drawings not found in logical place
    Address: Serra St.
  - Abrams, L. R., 1921-08-08; 39 (Box Sc1)
    7 sheets + 3 Sheets: Foundation, floor plans, elevations, details; A. B. Clark, 1921, pencil tracings
    Address: Sigma Nu Hill
  - Proctor, W. M., 1924-12-03; 219
    Address: Mirada & Dolores St.
  - Moreno, H. C., 1924-07-18; 207 (Box Sc10)
    9 drawings 6/30/1924
    Address: Mirada & San Juan Hill
  - Clark, A. B., 1928; 305
    [items may be gone according to note on card]
    Address: 618 Mirada
  - Swain, 1922; 152 (Box Sc1)
    5 sheets: window & door details, exterior elevations, plans, interior elevations, interior elevations & details; B. M. Clark, 1922, pencil tracings
    Address: 634 Mirada & Reservoir Drive
  - Vernier, C. G., 1922; 150 (Box Sc1)
    4 sheets: elevations, floor plans & interiors, foundation detials, details; B. M. Clark, 1922, pencil tracings
    Address: 675 Mirada, San Jaun Hill
  - Davis, J. S., 1922-07-08; 157 (Box Sc1)
    6 Sheets
    Address: 691 Mirada
  - Wilbur. alterations to # 267, 1942; 575 (Box Sc2)
    2 sheets, alterations to Stuart House
  - Stuart, Graham H., 1925-05-31; 267 (Box Sd9)
    7 sheets
  - Martin, E. G., 1926-04-01; 257 (Box Sd9)
    5 Sheets
    Address: Cabrillo Street
    City: Stanford University
  - Hoover, Lou Henry, 400
    garage addition, 1935
  - Roos, George; The Sullivan Auto Co., Garage, 1925-08-31; 246 (Box Sd9)
    5 Drawings
    Address: Alma St. betw. Hamilton and Forest
    City: Palo Alto
    Category: business
  - Spangler, C.B.; Palo Alto Sheet Metal Works, Shop Building, 1928-11-02; 320 (Box Sc9)
    6 drawings, 1928
    Address: Alma St.
  - Warren Furniture Co., Store, 1923-09; 189 (Box Sd8)
    8 Sheets
    Address: Alma, between Forest and Hamilton
  - Lansdale, Philip M.; Stover Tire and Service Station, 1928-04-02; 303 (Box Sc7)
    5 drawings, 1928
    Address: Alma St. and Everett Ave.
  - Pontiac Garage Building, 1936-05-08; 419 (Box Sc5)
    9 plans, 1936
    Address: Homer and High Sts.
  - Walters, W.; Dodge Garage, 239 (Box Sc10)
    8 drawings, June 9, 1925: elevations, plans, sections, details
    Address: 425 Alma (betw. University and Lytton)
  - Pratt, H.E.; Auto Electric Building, Additions and Remodeling, 306 (Box Sc7)
    5 drawings, May 5, 1928
    Address: Alma and Hamilton
  - Stanford Auto Co., 252
    Address: 511 Alma St.
  - Nathanson, Lester E., et. al.; Reinforced Concrete Store Building, 1939-11-21; 506 (Box Sb9)
    5 plans, 1939
    Address: 715-719 Alma St.
  - Byxbee, Mrs. A.L. and Jackson, Mrs. S.L.; Byxbee and Jackson, 1929-03-28; 153 (Box Sc1)
    2 sheets
    Address: 533 - 535 Bryant St.
  - Post Office and Professional Building, 1927-10-24; 291
    2 tubes, unopened
    Address: Hamilton Ave. and Ramona St.
  - Clark, Aleck; Safeway Store, 1932-12-16; 365 (Box Sc4)
    5 plans, 1932
    Address: 530 Bryant St.
  - Byxbee and Jackson; Byxbee and Jackson,; Altering Store Fronts, 1949-09-29; 683 (Box Sc3)
    2 sheets (from project 153) Sept. 14, 1948 (not tissue)
    Address: 535 537 539 Bryant St.
  - Palo Alto Hardware Co., 1929-08-24; 336 (Box Sc9)
    7 drawings
    Address: 522-524 Bryant St.
  - Palo Alto Hardware, New Stairs, 1933; 378 (Box Sc9)
    4 drawings (2 without file number). Rolled with number 347
    Address: 522 Bryant St.
  - Phillips, Dr. Hugh David; Dentist’s Office, 1933-11-06; 375 (Box Sc4)
    Plans
    Address: Byron and University Sts.
  - Smith, Jessie K., Allardice, R.E., Bartley, W.R.; Stores and Post Office, 1928-02-03; 295 (Box Sc7)
    Address: California Ave.
  - Sloan, W.H., 1945-10-06; 608 (Box Sc2)
    Store and Market Building, 7 drawings, 1945
  - Bishop, Stanley; Store Building, 1948-12-03; 682 (Box Sc3)
    4 sheets + 2 sheets on feb 1949 + 2 sheets on trace on march 1949
    Address: 392-398 California Ave.
  - Bartley, W.R., Smith, Jesse K., Merrill, Mrs. Phyllis M.; Garage, 1929-04; 326 (Box Sc9)
    5 drawings, 1929
    Address: 164 California Ave.
  - Roos, Maurice; Store Building and Warehouse, 670 (Box Sc3)
    Address: 415 California Ave.
  - Smith, Jessie K., 1925; 340 (Box Sc9)
    6 Drawings
    Address: 419-421 California Ave.
  - Braman, E.W.; Cabinet Shop, 635 (Box Sc6)
    2 plans, 1 elevation, 1946
    Address: 270 Cambridge Ave.
  - Masonic Temple Association, 251
    Address: University Ave. and Florence
  - Bullis, Richard S. & Bullis, Lorna S.; Nash Garage Building, 1946-02-14; 616 (Box Sc6)
    5 plans, 1946 - pencil on paper; 5 revised plans, 1946 - pencil on tissue
    Address: Channing & High Sts.
  - Clark-Stromquist Office Building, 1946-02; 617
    11 plans, 1946; Plans, some for furnishings, 1946 and 1951
    Address: 321 Channing Ave.
  - Norris, Charles; Outdoor Kitchen for Residence, 384
  - Norris, Charles G.; Residence, 293
    Address: Cowper Street & Melville Ave.
  - Norris, Charles G.; Basement Billiard Room Addition to Residence, 1931; 348 (Box Sc9)
    11 drawings
    Address: 1247 Cowper St.
  - Smith, Fred H.; Reinforced Concrete Store Building, 1937-02-19; 437 (Box Sc5)
    8 plans, 1937
    Address: On the Circle
    City: Palo Alto, CA
  - El Camino Electric Shop Building, 16615; 603 (Box Sc2)
    Four drawings, 1945
    Address: 2901 El Camino Real
  - Palo Alto Improvement Co. Garage and Stores, 1924-03-28; 201
    Address: Emerson St. betw. Hamilton and Forest Aves.
  - Wasserman; Hotel & Store Building, 1924-12-30; 225 (Box Sc10)
    12 drawings
    Address: Emerson betw. University & Lytton
  - Frazer Building Alterations, 573
    Jan. 2001 no drawings found
    Address: Emerson St.
  - Kee, Leung; Mandarin Grill, 1926-04-05; 259 (Box Sd9)
    6 sheets - only 5 sheets found
    Address: 544 Emerson St.
  - Acme Glass Co. Store and Shop, 492 (Box Sc8)
    2 plans, 1939
    Address: 635 Emerson St.
  - Hewlett-Packard Co., 1942-08-13; 577 (Box Sc2)
    One-Story Factory and Paint Shop, 4 drawings, 8/1/42
    Address: First St. & Page Mill Road
  - Blackburn, J.M.; Super Service Station, 245
    Not Supervised
    Address: Forest Ave. & Emerson St.
  - Wilbur, R.L. & Stephens, John S., Jr.; Peninsula Chevrolet, 412 (Box Sc5)
    6 plans for Garage Building, 1936
    Address: Forest & High Sts. (SW Corner of)
  - Johnson-Williams, Ltd. Factory Building, 1946-04-24; 622 (Box Sc6)
    3 plans, 1946 - pencil on paper
    Address: Grant Ave. and Third St.
  - Auto Electric Co. Battery Service Station, 1921-05-17; 34 (Box Sc1)
    2 sheets + 1 sheet
    Address: Hamilton Ave. & Alma St.
  - Pratt, H.E.; Auto Electric Building Addition and Remodeling, 306
  - Palo Alto Improvement Co.; Store Buildings, 1922-12-05; 168
    12 sheets ( some sheets are for job 712 modifications to the original stores)
    Address: 200-226 Hamilton
  - Peninsula Furniture Co., 1938; 467
    Address: Hamilton and Emerson
  - Enderson, E.C.; Store Building, 1925-03-23; 229 (Box Sc10)
    Address: Hamilton Ave & Ramona St.
  - Agnew, R.R.; Store Building, 1925-07-24; 240 (Box Sd9)
    4 drawings, July 30, 1925: plans, elevation
    Address: 106 Hamilton Ave.
  - Byxbee, Mrs. A.L. & Jackson, Mrs. S.L.; Three Stores, 1924-12-26; 213 (Box Sc10)
    Address: High Street
  - Dudfield Lumber Co., 1926-11; 276 (Box Sd9)
    5 sheets + 2 sheets of elevations
    Address: Corner of High & Channing Sts.
  - Widmann, C.; Dodge Garage Addition, 1928-05-11; 304 (Box Sc7)
    4 drawings, 1928
    Address: 430 High St.
  - Madison-Thoits Co., 1925-05-27; 233 (Box Sc10)
    5 sheets
    Address: 515 High St.
  - Thoits, Ed.; Madison-Thoits Store Alterations, 409
    1 floor plan, 1935
    Address: 156 University Ave.
  - Thomas, Dale H.; Shop Building, 1945-11-01; 611 (Box Sc2)
    4 plans, 1945
    Address: 635 High St.
  - Lee, Dr. Russell V.A. Palo Alto Clinic; Reinforced Concrete, Two-Story Doctors Office Building for Doctors Lee, Roth, Clark, & Wilbur, 1932-02-04; 359
    1 tube, unprocessed
    Address: NE Corner of Homer Ave & Bryant St.
  - Palo Alto Transfer and Storage One-Story Storage Warehouse, 1941-02-25; 438 (Box Sc11)
    7 plans, 1941 - marked "superceded"
    Address: Homer Ave. & High St.
  - Palo Alto Transfer & Storage, 1924-12-08; 220 (Box Sc10)
    21 drawings, 5 of which are from the 1945 construction of a new warehouse
    Address: 151 Homer St.
  - Palo Alto Transfer and Storage Co. Three- Story Warehouse Addition, 4381945
    Date of Contract: July 25, 1945
    Address: Homer & High Sts.
  - Hare, Brewer and Kelley; Tract Office for Leland Manor, 1941-07; 548 (Box Sc2)
    2 plans, n.d.
  - Palo Alto Times, 665
    Date of Contract: August 9, 1948
    Address: Lytton & Ramona Sts.
  - Dahl, John F. and Dahl, Mrs. John F.; Store Building, 1946-05-24; 607 (Box Sc2)
    4 drawings, 1946
    Address: 127 Lytton Ave.
  - Tinney Funeral Home Entrance Alterations, 1939-07-07; 499 (Box Sb9)
    2 plans, 1939 (1 has 1948 revisions on it)
    Address: 265 Lytton Ave.
  - Jack-Heintz-Ltd., 1940-07-27; 525 (Box Sb9)
    Address: 2815 Middlefield Rd.
  - Palo Alto National Bank, 321
    Date of Contract: Jan. 10, 1929
    Address: University Ave. & Ramona St.
  - Hare, Brewer & Clark; Crandall’s Homeware Shop, 292 (Box Sc7)
    9 drawings, 1927. Rolled with file #528
    Address: 541 Ramona St.
  - Allardice, R.E.; Ramona Building Remodeled, 195
    Address: Ramona St.
  - Hare, Brewer and Kelley Office, 630 (Box Sc6)
    1 plan of alteration to front, 1946 - pencil on tissue
  - Palo Alto Mutual Building & Loan (Building Razed 1964 ), 1947-02-11; 639 (Box Sc6)
    10 plans, 1947
    Address: 515 Ramona St.
  - Thoits, Edward C. & Lansdale, P.N.; Store Building, 274 (Box Sc11)
    Date of Contract: Oct. 7, 1926 [not yet reviewed]
  - Hare, Brewer and Kelley; Store Building adjoining Professional Building, 1927-12-20; 292
    2 blueprints (first floor & basement plan) - BRITTLE
  - Palo Alto Improvement Co.; Three Stores, 1928-02-17; 280 (Box Sc7)
    8 sheets - plans, elevations, sections & structural details.; 3 revision sheets - plans and details
    Address: 538-542 Ramona St
  - Crandall's Homeware Store Additions, 528 (Box Sc7)
    1 drawing, 1940; rolled with file #292
  - Richter, Adolf; Stanford Upholstering Co. Store Building, 1927-10-01; 290 (Box Sc7)
    Address: 628-630 Ramona St.
  - Cranston, W. & Gertrude M Gardner; Revision of Old Liddicoat's Market, 1924-02-12; 198 (Box Sd8)
    2 Sheets
    Address: University Ave.
  - Palo Alto National Bank Building, 1937-05-27; 444 (Box Sc5)
    11 plans, 1937
    Address: 250 University Ave.
  - Baker, J. Jay; Jewelry Store Alterations, 425 (Box Sc5)
    1 plan, 1936 ["Store alterations for Tom Christy"]
    Address: University Ave. near Waverley St.
  - Lansdale, Phillip M.; Varsity Theatre Remodeled into Stores, 1928-02-19; 288 (Box Sc7)
    5 drawings, 1927
    Address: 456 University Ave. betw. Bryant and Ramona
  - Strub, Dr. Charles H.; Stores, 1927-06-27; 284 (Box Sc7)
    17 drawings, 1927
    Address: University Ave. betw. Bryant & Waverley Sts.
  - Hyde-Harrier Store, 1922; 185 (Box Sd8)
    7 sheets (dated 1922), 2 sheets, and 1 blueprint.; 185 is the file number from the Clark file cards, but the tissue sheets are marked File No. 649. Since 649 was used for a school in Centerville, these drawings are being filed under 185. The date (1922) would also argue for the earlier File Number as the 600 file numbers date from the 1940s.
    Address: University Ave. near Waverley
  - Wisdom, P.L.; Bungalow Courts, 1922-12-14; 167
    7 Sheets
    Address: University and Cowper Sts.
  - Blackburn, J.M.; President Hotel / apartment building, 1929-11-05; 339
    Set of 19 drawings, Sept. 10, 1929 with about 4 additional drawings dated 1930 (pencil on tissue); wrapped in 1971 drawing (bond paper)
    Address: 480 - 498 University and Cowper
  - Cranston, Carol D. & Smith, Jessie K.; Cranston-Smith Building, 1923-05-21; 183 (Box Sd8)
    6+1 Sheet
    Address: University & Waverley
  - Thoits, W.C.; Roos Brothers Store Building, 1925-04-25; 230 (Box Sc10)
    13 drawings
    Address: 125 University Ave.
  - Peninsula Homes, 439 (Box Sc5)
    Office revisions, 1 plan, 1937
    Address: 150 University Ave.
  - Brown, G. F.; Madison-Thoits Warehouse, 242
    1 drawing: remodeling building, plans & elevations, July 14, 1925
    Address: 162 University Ave.
  - Thoits, E.C.; Store Building, 436 (Box Sc5)
    4 plans, 1937
    Address: 174 University Ave.
  - Wideman & Son, Inc. Store Building, 1936-06-11; 428 (Box Sc5)
    Series of 6 plans, 1936
    Address: 180 University Ave.
  - American Trust Co.; Palo Alto Mutual Bank Building, 1937; 443 (Box Sc5)
    Address: 212 University Ave.
    Category: city project
  - Porter, B.L.; Old Stanford Theater Remodeled into Stores, 1925-07-22; 244 (Box Sd9)
    Address: 215 University Ave.
  - Carey, George J.; Store, 1926-05-04; 265 (Box Sd9)
    7 Sheets + 1 Sheet of revision + 3 Sheets of Blue prints
    Address: 218 University
  - University Realty Co., 1928 Dec-1929 Feb; 322 (Box Sc9)
    2 drawings, 1928
    Address: 233 University Ave.
  - Gardiner, Miss Gertrude M.; Store Building Alterations, 1934-04-27; 382 (Box Sc4)
    3 plans, 1934
    Address: 270 - 276 University Ave.
  - Murphy, Jennie L. & Bessie W.; Store Building Alteration, 1934-06-27; 385 (Box Sc4)
    2 drawings, 1934 and 3 color elevations for store entrance, n.d.
  - Pitman, Mary L.; Pitman Store Building Addition, 1938-03-22; 453 (Box Sc5)
    Address: 260 University Ave.
  - Spiro, Dr. Harry; Store Building, 1929-06-20; 332 (Box Sc9)
    8 drawings, 1929
    Address: 266 University Ave.
  - Palo Alto Hardware Co. Storefront Remodeling, 1930; 347 (Box Sc9)
    2 drawings; Memo Specifications Dated: March 26, 1930
    Address: 278 University Ave.
  - Cranston, William & Gardiner, Miss G.M.; Store Revision, 255 (Box Sd9)
    6 sheets + 1 blue print
    Address: 303 University Ave.
  - Barry, Frank R.; Shoe Store, 1945-10-16; 609 (Box Sc2)
    8 plans, 1945 - pencil on tissue
    Address: 317 University Ave.
  - Crandall, B.W.; Store, 1925-07-30; 241 (Box Sd9)
    3 drawings, July 17, 1925: plans, elevations, details
    Address: 323 University Ave.
  - Cranston & Smith; Liddicoat’s Market Store Building, 1923-12-07; 188 (Box Sd8)
    Address: 340 University Ave.
  - Plymire, Mrs. Annie F. & Lawson, Miss Jennie E.; Store Building, 1927-07-06; 285 (Box Sc7)
    4 sheets + 1 revised sheet - Plans, section, elevation (terracota details), Details.
    Address: 423, 425 University Ave.
  - McDougall, Mrs. Mattie; Store Building, 1937-06-23; 450 (Box Sc5)
    5 plans, 1937
    Address: 427 University Ave.
  - Plymire, Mrs. Annie F.; Store Building, 1926-09-13; 271 (Box Sd9)
    Address: 429, 433, 437 University Ave.
  - Rudee, Dr. Mervyn C.; One-Story Store Building, 1935-10-02; 402 (Box Sc4)
    9 items - pencil on paper
    Address: 453 University Ave.
    Architect: Clark, Birge M. and David C. Clark
  - Peterson, A.B.; Store Building, 463 (Box Sc8)
    Address: 463 University Ave.
  - Rudee, Dr. Mervyn C.; Moody’s Store Building Addition, 1945-12-04; 614 (Box Sc6)
    5 plans, 1946
  - Hoffacker, B.J.; Store Building, 1927; 281 (Box Sc7)
    8 Sheets - Plans, elevations, sections & structural details
    Address: 526, 530, 534 Waverley St.
  - Davis, Dr. Burt; Garage Addition, 647 (Box Sc6)
    1 plan, 1947
  - Phillips, Dr. Hugh David; Dentist's Office Building, 1945-04-05; 605 (Box Sc2)
    Plans, 1945; ROLLED WITH FILE # 375
    Address: Byron & University Sts.
  - Frazer, J.; Store Building Addition, 1924-06; 206 (Box Sc10)
    Roll 1: 9 drawings, pencil and ink on tissue, 1924; Roll 2: 3 blueprints of plumbing/heating 1924; Roll 3: 8 Sheets 1924
    Address: University & Emerson
  - City of Palo Alto; Palo Alto Police and Fire Station, 1927-04-28; 249
    Blueprints (Steel Construction Company), 1927 - BRITTLE, SOME ARE DAMAGED
    Address: Bryant St. between University & Lytton Ave.
  - City of Palo Alto; City Hall Additions, 1922-05-01; 156 (Box Sc1)
    7 sheets + 1 sheet (not tissue - vellum?)
  - City of Palo Alto; Automobile Sheds for City of Palo Alto, 294 (Box Sc7)
    1 drawing, no date
  - City of Palo Alto; Community Theater, 367 (Box Sc11)
    Date of Contract: Jan. 26, 1933 [not yet reviewed]
    Address: Rinconada Park
  - City of Palo Alto; Community Theater Wing A, 374
    Date of Contract: Oct. 23, 1933
  - City of Palo Alto; Community Theater Ruth Stern Wing & Wing B, 377
    Date of Contract: March 9, 1934
  - City of Palo Alto; Community Theater New Wing for Children’s Theater and Boy Scout Rooms, 427
    Date of Contract: June 10, 1936
  - City of Palo Alto; Community Theater Children’s Theater Kitchen, 459
    1 plan, 1937
  - City of Palo Alto; Boy Scouts (Community Center ) Fire Circle, 1938-11-16; 484 (Box Sc8)
    Boy Scout Fire Circle, PA Comm. Center, 1938 (1 item); Proposed Camp Development for the Stanford Area Council BSA in Pinecrest, CA (1 orig & 1 copy)
    Architect: Birge M. And David C. Clark
  - City of Palo Alto; Ruth Lucie Stern Childrens' Library for the City of Palo Alto, 516
    Date of Contract: April 23, 1940
  - City of Palo Alto; Community Center Theater Workshop, 672
    Date of Contract: June 18, 1948
  - City of Palo Alto; Girl Scout House, 448 (Box Sc5)
    6 plans, 1937
  - City of Palo Alto; Palo Alto Library Addition, 1922-05-31; 149
    7 plans, ink on linen, 1922; approx. 4 plans on tissue, 1922 [some of these are damaged]
    Address: Hamilton & Bryant
  - Chamber of Commerce; Chamber of Commerce Chapel in the Sky, 1941-12; 563 (Box Sc2)
    Drawings have no date, no place
  - Palo Alto Clinic, Ltd.; Clinic Addition, 1946-07-20; 627 (Box Sc11)
    24 items: A1 thru A19 (Floor Plans & Details); S1 thru S5; 1 item: "Second floor change" Nov. 5, 1946
    Address: Bryant St. & Homer
  - Palo Alto Clinic, Ltd.; Clinic Addition Finishing of Second Floor, 460 (Box Sc11)
    1 drawings: plan, interiors & details, Sept. 1937
    Address: 300 Homer
  - Palo Alto Clinic, Ltd.; Palo Alto Clinic Temporary Lean-To, 598
    Date of Contract: Feb. 1944; Jan. 2001 no drawings found
    Address: Bryant St.
  - Smith, Allardice & Bartley; California Ave. Theater, 1926-04-31; 263 (Box Sd9)
  - Red Cross (American); Red Cross (American), 1946-1947; 623 (Box Sc6)
    5 plans, 1946 - pencil on paper
    Address: El Camino Park
  - B.P.O.E. Lodge; Lodge Building for B.P.O.E. No. 1471, 1941-08; 537 (Box Sb9)
    17 plans, 1941
    Address: 4249 El Camino Real
  - Fisher Research Laboratories; Fisher Research Laboratories One-Story Shop Addition, 1943-03-08; 584 (Box Sc2)